Guide to the James O. Brown Associates Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Author File
  - Vielle, E.E. & Donald Payne (Box 366)
    ("Donald Gordon")
  - Vigeveno, Henk S. (Box 366)
  - Villard, Henry Serrano (Box 367)
  - Vinaver, Eugene (Box 367)
  - Vincent, Sally (Box 367)
  - Vinson, Curtis (Box 367)
  - Visson, Andre (Box 367)
  - Vitak, Albertina (Box 367)
  - Vittorini, Elio (Box 367)
  - Von Bucovich, Annie & Louis D. Froelick (Box 367)
  - Waagenaar, Sam (Box 367)
  - Wade, Rosalind Herschel (Box 367)
  - Wagner, Constance (Box 367)
  - Wagner, Donald (Box 367)
  - Wagner, Linda (Box 367)
  - Wain, John Barrington (Box 367)
  - Wainright, Loudon (Box 367)
  - Wakefield, Dan (Box 368-369)
  - Wakefield, Herbert Russell (Box 370)
  - Wakefield, Walter L. (Box 370)
  - Waldo, George C. (Box 370)
  - Waldron, Webb (Box 370)
  - Wale, Michael (Box 370)
  - Wales, Henry (Box 370)
  - Wales, Leonard A. (Box 370)
  - Walker, Alexander (Box 370)
  - Walker, Benjamin (Box 370)
  - Walker, Betty Compton (Mrs. James J.) (Box 370)
  - Walker, Dale Morris (Box 370)
  - Walker, Frank Comerford (Box 370)
  - Walker, Mildred Merrifield (Box 370)
  - Walker, Oliver (Box 370)
  - Walker, Stanley (Box 370)
  - Wall, Bernard (Box 370)
  - Wallace, Frank R. (Box 370)
  - Wallace, John (Box 370)
  - Wallace, Ralph (Box 370)
  - Wallenstein, Marcel H. (Box 370)
  - Walsh, John G., Jr. (Box 371)
  - Walsh, W. Thomas (Box 371)
  - Walter, Karl (Box 371)
  - Walter, Wilfred (Box 371)
  - Walton, George (Box 371)
  - Walton, Mary (Box 371)
  - Walton, Todd (Box 371)
  - Wang, King C. (Box 371)
  - Warburg, Fredric John (Box 371)
  - Ward, Marion (Box 371)
  - Ware, Runa Erwin (Box 371)
  - Warga, Claire L (Box 371)
  - Warner, Denis & Peggy S. (Box 372)
  - Warner, Douglas & Elizabeth Florence Warner (Box 372)
  - Warner, Kenneth (Box 372)
    ("Dighton Morel")
  - Warner, Oliver (Box 372)
  - Warner, Robert (Box 372)
  - Warner, Tori (Victoria M. Warner) (Box 372)
  - Warren, George (Box 372)
  - Warren, Joyce (Box 372)
  - Washburn, Watson & Edmund S. DeLong (Box 372)
  - Wasserman, John L. (Box 372)
  - Wathen, Richard B. (Box 372)
  - Watkyn, Arthur (A.T.L. Watkins) (Box 372)
  - Watson, Geoffrey S. (Jef Watson) (Box 372)
  - Watt, Ian (Box 372)
  - Wayburn, Ned (Box 373)
  - Wayne, P. & D. Marianoff (Box 373)
  - Wead, Frank W. (Box 373)
  - Weber, Nancy (Box 373)
  - Weber, Thomas B. (Box 373)
  - Webster, Horace Tucker (Box 373)
  - Webster, Samuel Charles & Doris Webster (Box 373)
  - Weekes, Cyrus P. (Box 373)
  - Weems, Benjamin Francis (Box 373)
  - Weglyn, Michi "Michi" (Box 374)
  - Weigall, Arthur Edvard Pearse Brome, Muriel Frances Lillie Weigall Dean Paul, Sir Brian Kenneth Dean Paul "Napier Dean Paul" (Box 374)
  - Weil, Barry (Derek Robert) (Box 374)
  - Weil, Margaret Hertz (Box 374)
  - Weinberg, Herman G. (Box 374)
  - Weiner, Jack B. (Box 374)
  - Weitz, Dorothy Goodman (Box 374)
  - Wellborn, Marguerite A. (Mrs. Arthur) (Box 374)
  - Weld, Carol (Box 374)
  - Weldon, John Lee (Box 374)
  - Wellard, James H (Box 374)
  - Wells, A. Bancroft (Box 374)
  - Wells, Carolyn (Box 374)
  - Wells, John (Box 374)
  - Wells, Walter A. (Box 374)
  - Wender, Dorothea (Box 374)
  - Wendt, Albert (Box 374)
  - Wertham, Fredric (Box 375)
  - Wertenbaker, Charles (Box 375)
  - West, Dorothy & Marian Minus (Box 375)
  - West, Francis J. (Box 375)
  - West, Dame Rebecca (Box 375)
  - Westminster, Loelia Mary Ponsonby Grosvenor, Duchess of (Box 375)
  - Wetmore, William (Box 376)
  - Wheeler, Terence (Box 376)
  - Whelan, Elizabeth M. (Box 376)
  - Wheldon, Jacqueline Mary Clarke (Box 376)
  - Whipple, Hollis Letts McLaughlin (Box 376)
  - White, Alan (Box 376)
    ("James Fraser", "Alec Haig")
  - White, Edmund (Box 376)
  - White, G. Edward (Box 376)
  - White, John (Box 376)
  - White, John W. (Box 376)
  - White, Owen P. (Box 377)
  - White, Patrick Victor Martindale (Box 377)
  - White, Reginald J. (Box 377)
  - White, Richard Glynn (Box 377)
  - White, Robin (Box 377-378)
  - White, Terence de Tere (Box 379)
  - White, Trumbull (Box 379)
  - White, William Allen (Box 379)
  - White, William S. (Box 379)
  - Whiteson, Leon (Box 379)
  - Whitlock, Bache McEvers (Box 379)
  - Whitman, Alden (Box 379)
  - Whitton, Mary Ormsbee (Box 379)
  - Whyte, Thomas (Box 379)
  - Wick, Patricia O'Tool (Box 380)
  - Wickers, David (Box 380)
  - Wickham, Lillie (Box 380)
  - Widmark, Eric (Box 380)
  - Wiggins, Marianne (Box 380)
  - Wignall, Anne (Box 380)
    ("Alice Acland")
  - Wilcox, Harry (Box 380)
    ("Mark Derby")
  - Wilde, Hagar (Box 380)
  - Wilder, Laura Elizabeth Ingalls (Box 380)
  - Wilding, Michael (Box 380)
  - Wiley, Dwight Mitchell (Box 381)
  - Wiley, Hugh (Box 381)
  - Wilhelm, Donald (Box 381)
  - Wilhelm, Edmund (Box 381)
  - Willemse, Cornelius W. (Box 381)
  - Willets, Ann (Box 381)
  - Willetts, Fred W. (Box 381)
  - Williams, C. Dickerman (Box 381)
  - Williams, Christopher (Box 381)
  - Williams, Duncan (Box 381)
  - Williams, Elaine (Elaine Stewart), Robert Williams, & Brinda Maharani of Kapurthala (Box 381)
  - Williams, Elma M. (Box 381)
  - Williams, Francis (Edward Francis Williams, Baron Francis-Williams) (Box 382)
  - Williams, Guy (Box 382)
  - Williams, Gwyn (Box 382)
  - Williams, Miller (Box 382)
  - Williams, Norman Lloyd (Box 382)
  - Williams, Ursula Moray (Ursula Moray John) (Box 382)
  - Williams, Wythe (Box 382)
  - Williamson, Audrey (Box 382)
  - Williamson, David (Box 382)
  - Williamson, Hudleston Noel Hedworth (Box 382)
  - Williamson, Samuel T. (Box 382)
  - Williamson, Tony (Box 382)
  - Williamson, Walter (Box 382)
  - Willock, Colin (Box 383)
  - Willock, Ruth (Box 383)
  - Wills, Frederick Rudolph (Box 383)
  - Wills, Helen Newington (Helen Wills Moody) (Box 383)
  - Wilner, Herbert (Box 383-384)
  - Wilson, Angus Frank Johnstone (Box 384)
  - Wilson, John (Box 384)
  - Wilson, John Rowan (John Robinson Wilson) (Box 384)
  - Wilson, Morrow (Box 384)
  - Wilson, Rosalind (Box 384)
    ("Rosalind Cathie")
  - Wilson, Sandy- (Box 385)
  - Wilson, Steve (Box 385)
  - Wilson, William Edward (Box 385)
  - Winant, John Gilbert (Box 386)
  - Winberg, Eric T. (Box 386)
  - Winn, Marcia (Box 386)
  - Winnick, Harriet (Box 386)
  - Winslow, Seymour (Box 386)
  - Winslow, Thyra Samter (Box 386)
  - Winsor, Diana (Box 386)
  - Wise, Arthur (Box 386)
  - Wise, Evelyn Voss (Box 386)
  - Wise, Leo (Box 386)
  - Wittenberg, Henry (Box 386)
  - Wohl, Burton (Box 386)
  - Wolf, Howard Robert (Box 386)
  - Wolf, Sam (Box 386)
  - Wolfe, Linda (Box 386)
  - Wolfe, Tom (Thomas Kennerly Wolfe, Jr (Box 386)
  - Wolfe, Winifred (Box 386)
  - Wolff, William Almon (Box 386)
  - Wolfson, Murray (Box 386)
  - Wood, Herbert Fairlie (Box 387)
  - Wood, James Playsted (Box 387)
  - Wood, Junius B. (Box 387)
  - Wood, William P. (Box 388)
  - Wood, Ysabella (Margaret Hall Wood! (Box 389)
  - Woodhouse, Christopher Montague (Box 389)
  - Woodthorpe, Michael W. (Box 389)
  - Woodward, Harry Evans (Box 389)
  - Wooldridge, David (Box 389)
  - Wooldridge, Susan "Susanna Martin", Colin Rowland Corder, Claude R. Johnson, & Keith London (Box 390)
  - Woolf, Samuel Johnson (Box 390)
  - Woollcott, Alexander (Box 390)
  - Woollcott, Barbara (Box 390)
  - Woolley, Robert Wickliffe (Box 390)
  - Woon, Basil (Box 390)
  - Worden, Helen (Box 390)
  - Worsley, Isobel (Box 390)
  - Worthington, Dorothy (Box 390)
  - Wortis, Avi & Jodi Robbin (Box 390)
  - Wright, Austin (Box 390)
  - Wright, Brian (Box 390)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd (Box 390)
  - Wright, Robert (Box 390)
  - Wright, Sidney Fowler (Box 390)
  - Wright, Stephen (Box 390)
  - Wright, William C. (Box 390)
  - Wurtman, Judith J. (Box 391)
  - Wurtzebach, David (Box 391)
  - Wynn, Edgar J. (Box 391)
  - Wynne, Barry (Box 391)
  - Wynne Jones, Diana (Box 391)
  - Yaffé, Maurice (Box 391)
  - Yanni, Nicholas (Box 391)
  - Yardley, Herbert Osborn (Box 391)
  - Ybarra, Thomas Russell (Box 391)
  - Yoder, Robert McAyeal (Box 391)
  - Yorke, Margaret (Margaret Nicholson) (Box 391)
  - Yosso, Melvin L. (Box 391)
  - Young, Art (Arthur Henry Young) (Box 392)
  - Young, Elizabeth Coleman (Box 392)
  - Young, James C. (Box 392)
  - Young, John Richard (Box 392)
  - Young, Ken & John Kramer (Box 392)
  - Young, Perry Deane (Box 392)
  - Young, Warren R. (Box 392)
  - Yudain, Harold (Box 392)
  - Yurka, Blanche (Box 392)
  - Zalamea, Luis (Box 393)
  - Zam, Maurice (Box 393)
  - Zeligs, Meyer A. (Box 393)
  - Zich, Arthur (Box 393)
  - Ziegler, Richard S, & Patrick F. Flaherty (Box 394)
  - Ziff, William B. (Box 394)
  - Zilliacus, Stella (Box 394)
  - Zim, Marvin (Box 394)
  - Zion, Sidney (Box 394)
  - Zohar, Danah (Box 394)
  - Zoll, Stephen (Box 394)
  - Zolotow, Maurice (Box 394)
  - Zorza, Rosemary (Box 394)
- Series IV: Agents, Publishers, Magazines, Corporates Names, & Subject File
  - A--Miscellaneous (Box 395)
  - American… (Box 395)
  - The American Magazine (Box 395)
  - The American Mercury (Box 395)
  - American Play Company, Inc. (Box 395)
  - American Red Cross (Box 395)
  - The American Weekly (Box 395)
  - D. Appleton-Century Company (Box 395)
  - Argosy (Box 395)
  - Asia Magazine (Box 395)
  - Aspenwall, Marguerite AGT (Box 395)
  - The Atlantic Monthly (Box 395)
  - Australia (Box 395)
  - Barbour & McKeogh, Inc. AGT (Box 395)
  - The Bell Syndicate, Inc. (Box 395)
  - Bing, Edward J.-Intercontinental Press Corporation, Ltd. AGT (Box 395)
  - Birnbaum, Agnes-NAL (Box 395)
  - Blank, Dorothy Ann AGT (Box 396)
  - Blond & Briggs Publishers (Box 396)
  - The Bobbs-Merrill Company Publishers (Box 396)
  - Bodin, Ed AGT (Box 396)
  - Casa Editrice Valentino Bompiani & C. (Box 396)
  - Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc. (Box 396)
  - Bradley, Jenny Serruys (Mrs. William A.) AGT (Box 396)
  - Brandt & Brandt AGT (Box 396)
  - Bushman, Annette (Box 396)
  - Thornton Butterworth Ltd. Publishers (Box 396)
  - Bye, George T.: Personal; George T. Bye & Company-James Brown Associates--merger AGT (Box 396)
  - C--Miscellaneous (Box 397)
  - Jonathan Cape, Ltd.: Jonathan Cape & Robert Ballou, Inc; Jonathan Cape & Harrison Smith, Inc. Publishers--bankruptcy proceedings (Box 397)
  - The Chicago Tribune (Box 397)
  - Clayton, Frederick (Box 397)
  - Click; the national picture monthly (Box 397)
  - Cohen, Albert J, AGT (Box 397)
  - College Humor (Box 397)
  - Collier & Flinn Co., Ltd. AGT (Box 397)
  - Collier's; the national weekly (Box 397)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc (Box 397)
  - Columbia, University; Maria Moors Cabot Award (Box 397)
  - Contract Forms (Box 397-398)
  - Copyrights (Box 399)
  - Copyright renewals (Box 399)
  - Cosmopolitan (Box 399)
  - Country Gentleman (Box 399)
  - Coward-McCann, Inc. Publishers (Box 399)
  - Cross & Brown Company Real Estate (Box 399)
  - Thomas Y. Crowell Company Publishers (Box 399)
  - Current Reading (Box 399)
  - Curtis Brown Ltd. AGT (Box 399)
  - D--Miscellaneous (Box 400)
  - Peter Davies Limited Publishers (Box 400)
  - The John Day Company Inc. Publishers (Box 400)
  - Denby, R.J.B. AGT (Box 400)
  - The Dial Press (Box 400)
  - David Diamond Literary Agency (Box 400)
  - Dodd, Mead and Company Inc. Publishers (Box 401)
  - Doubleday, Doran and Company, Inc., Publishers (Box 401)
  - Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc. Publishers (Box 401)
  - E.P. Dutton & Co., Inc. Publishers (Box 401)
  - H.E. Edington-F.W. Vincent, Inc. AGT (Box 401)
  - Esquire (Box 401)
  - F--Miscellaneous (Box 401)
  - John Farquharson Ltd. AGT (Innes Rose) (Box 401)
  - Farrar & Rinehart, Inc. Publishers (Box 401)
  - Fawcett Publications Incorporated (Box 401)
  - Fiction Parade (Box 401)
  - Form letters (Box 401)
  - Fortune (Box 401)
  - The Forum (Box 401)
  - Fuller, Muriel (Box 401)
  - Furst, Myra AGT (Box 401)
  - Gelsey, Erwin S. (Box 401)
  - Globe Productions, Inc. (James Roosevelt) (Box 401)
  - Good Housekeeping (Box 401)
  - Goodhue, Robert Kendall AGT (Box 401)
  - Greenbaum, Wolff & Ernst (Box 401)
  - The Griswold-Eshleman Co. Advertising (Box 401)
  - Hammell, John A. AGT (Box 402)
  - Harper & Brothers Publishers (Box 402)
  - Hart, William B. (Box 402)
  - Hedin, Naboth (Box 402)
  - Holiday House, Inc, [Publishers] (Box 402)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company [Publishers] (Box 402)
  - Hovey, Carl AGT (Box 402)
  - Incorporated Society of Authors’' Representatives AGT (Box 402)
  - John Johnson AGT (Box 402)
  - Joss, John-The Practical Press (Box 402)
  - Kansas City Star (Box 402)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. [Publishers] (Box 402)
  - Kunkis, Sol R. (Box 402)
  - Ladies’ Home Journal (Box 403)
  - Lamkin, Marguerite (Box 403)
  - Laska, Edward AGT (Box 403)
  - Lennen & Mitchell, Inc. Advertising (Box 403)
  - J.B. Lippincott Company Publishers (Box 403)
  - Little, Brown & Company Publishers (Box 403)
  - Longlams, Green & Co., Inc. Publishers (Box 403)
  - A. and S. Lyons, Inc. AGT (Box 403)
  - M--Miscellaneous (Box 403)
  - Robert M. McBride & Company Publishers (Box 403)
  - McCall's Magazine (Box 404)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc. (Box 404)
  - The Macmillan Company Publishers (Box 404)
  - Magazine Digest (Box 404)
  - Malkiel, Henrietta (Box 404)
  - Martin, Quinn (Box 404)
  - Julian Messner, Inc. Publishers (Box 404)
  - Metro-Goldwyn-May er Pictures (Box 404)
  - William Morrow & Company, Inc. Publishers (Box 404)
  - N--Miscellaneous (Box 404)
  - National Broadcasting Company, Inc. (Box 404)
  - New York Herald Tribune (Box 404)
  - The New York Times (Box 404)
  - North American Newspaper Alliance, Inc. (Box 404)
  - Charles F. Noyes Company, Inc. Real Estate (Box 404)
  - Q'Laughlin, John Callan--Army Navy Journal (Box 404)
  - Paramount Pictures Corporation (Box 404)
  - Pearn, Pollinger & Higham, Ltd. AGT (Box 405)
  - Laurence Pollinger Limited AGT (Box 406)
  - Murray Pollinger AGT (Box 406)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc. [Publishers] (Box 406)
  - G.P. Putnam's Sons[Publishers] & George Palmer Putnam, Inc. (Box 406)
  - Rackham Film Productions, Ltd. (Box 406)
  - RCA Global Communications, Inc. (Box 406)
  - The Reader’s Digest (Box 406-407)
  - Reinheimer, Howard E. (Box 407)
  - Renova, Anne AGT (Box 407)
  - Reynolds, Goodwin, Wilson & Flack (Box 407)
  - Reynolds, Jacqueline AGT (Box 407)
  - Rhodes, June Hamilton (Box 407)
  - S--Miscellaneous (Box 407)
  - Salmon, Clarke (Box 407)
  - Samples, Ruhl M. AGT (Box 407)
  - Sydney A. Sanders AGT (Box 407)
  - The Saturday Evening Post (Box 408)
  - Saunders, Marion AGT (Box 409)
  - Schley & Leonardson AGT (Box 409)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons Publishers (Box 409)
  - Sears Publishing Company, Inc. (Box 409)
  - Myron Selznick & Company AGT (Box 409)
  - Oscar Serlin Productions (Box 409)
  - Siegel, Jerome S. AGT (Box 409)
  - Simon & Schuster, Inc. Publishers (Box 409-410)
  - Smith, Lawrence AGT (Box 410)
  - Society of Authors’ Representatives, Inc. (Box 410)
  - Spitzer, Philip G. AGT (Box 410)
  - Spokesmen (Curtis Brown Group Ltd.) (Box 410)
  - Frederick A, Stokes Company Publishers (Box 411)
  - Strauss, Florence AGT (Box 411)
  - Survival Anglis Limited (Box 411)
  - H.N. Swanson, Inc. AGT (Box 411-412)
  - T--Miscellaneous (Box 413)
  - Talley, Truman M. (Box 413)
  - This Week (Box 413)
  - Tower Magazines, Inc. (Box 413)
  - Translators (Box 413)
  - Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation (Box 413)
  - United Artists Corporation (Box 413)
  - United Feature Syndicate, Inc. (Box 413)
  - U.S. Office of Government Reports--Lowell Mellett (Box 413)
  - Universal Pictures Corporation (Box 413)
  - The University of Chicago Press (Box 413)
  - V--Miscellaneous (Box 413)
  - The Vanguard Press (Box 413)
  - Vanity Fair (Box 413)
  - The Viking Press, Inc. Publishers (Box 413)
  - Vogue (Box 413)
  - W--Miscellaneous (Box 413)
  - War Department (Box 413)
  - Warner Bros, Pictures, Inc. (Box 413)
  - Ann Watkins, Inc. AGT (Box 413)
  - A.P. Watt & Son AGT (Box 413)
  - White, Ralph W. AGT (Box 413)
  - C.C. Wilkening & Son, Inc. A GT (Box 413)
  - Williams, Annie Laurie AGT (Box 413)
  - Wing, Willis Kingsley AGT (Box 413)
  - Woman's Day (Box 413)
  - Woman's Home Companion (Box 413)
  - The World's Fair of 1940 in New York (Box 413)
  - World's Work (Box 413)
  - Writers' War Board (Box 413)
  - Yank (Box 413)
  - Young & Rubicam, Inc. (Box 413)
  - Your Life (Box 413)
  - Youth Today (Box 413)
  - Ziff-Davis Publishing Company (Box 413)
- Series V: James Oliver Brown--Personal Correspondence
  - General, 1941-1957 (Box 414)
  - On his illness and retirement, 1985 (Box 414)
  - Correspondence since retirement, 1985-1988 (Box 414)
  - Century Association, 1982 (Box 414)
- Series VI: Contracts
  - No. 1-200 (Box 415)
  - No. 201-400 (Box 416)
  - No. 401-650 (Box 417)
  - No. 651-850 (Box 418)
  - No. 851-1100 (Box 419)
  - No. 1101-1369 (Box 420)
- Series VII: Financial Papers, 1931-1977
  - Account Books
    - Expense Accounts, 1949-1951 (Box 421)
    - 1949-1955 (Box 421)
    - 1950-1956 (Box 421)
    - Erskine Caldwell, 1951-1960 (Box 422)
    - Expense Accounts, 1952-1955 (Box 422)
    - Accountants and Ledger Sheets, 1952-1958 (Box 422)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 422)
    - 1956-1958 (Box 423)
    - Petty Cash, 1957 (Box 423)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 423)
    - 1959-1960 (2) (Box 424)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 424)
    - Card File, 1960-1961 (Box 424)
    - 1963 (Box 424)
    - Card File, 1970 (Box 425)
    - Ledger Sheets, 1969-1977 (Box 425)
  - Bank Statements & Cancelled Checks, 1931-1958 (Box 427-442)
  - Banks
    - Check Stubs, 1949-1958 (Box 442-444)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1958 (Box 444)
  - Bills--Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 444)
  - Taxes, 1928-1958 (Box 445)
  - Travel, 1948-1958 (Box 446)